I feel bad for the mice.
Okay, I'll stomp out the bad guys,
while you all keep them from—
You can't.
Huh? Why not?
Because the hole will collapse and none of them will survive.
And that won't solve anything.
That's right.
We have to play by the rules to beat this world.
Otherwise, we won't get our reward.
Nozomi!
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Thanks.
Is there actually any point in doing this?
Well...
This one won't lead us anywhere either.
We won't know unless we try.
I-I'm beat.
Are you okay?
Here, drink this.
He made it to a few of the worlds we were aiming for, didn't he?
True, but it felt like that was only really by chance.
Like a luck-of-the-draw gacha machine?
You'll hit the jackpot eventually, just keep on trying.
I somehow doubt it's going to be that simple.
I'm sorry.
Oh? What are you apologizing for?
The more failures we have,
the greater our chances of succeeding.
That's right. We have as many tomorrows here as we need.
Yeah...
There's no guarantee that this is going to go on forever, is there?
That may be true.
And leaving this up to chance won't help us either.
We've found a signpost to our original world,
and a means of moving ourselves there.
But what is it that connects the two?
Whether it's someone's power,
or this world itself, we can't be sure.
But finding another piece to the puzzle should help.
Handily, newly-discovered powers take on many different forms.
Yeah, and the light is closer, too.
Closer today than yesterday.
Okay!
Let's set these mice free.
It's not like all hope is lost in this world.
We'll save the revolutionary mouse,
and shift the way things work in this world.
A world where gold isn't everything—
there must be another level with a different paradigm.
Operation Mouse Relocation!
Have we beaten the world?
You're getting better at using your power.
Huh? You think so?
It doesn't feel like anything has changed.
Nah, it's changed a bunch.
Seeing your improvement makes me think we can make it home soon.
Surely you're exaggerating.
Then again, remember what Ms. Aki said?
You know, how we'll never...
Don't pay her any mind.
A doctor at the hospital once told me,
"Never ever trust anything that comes out of a large-breasted woman's mouth."
You see, all the nutrients go to her boobs—
A-All right, I get it!
Ah! You're blushing!
Hey, could this be this world's reward?
Whoa.
They came undone?
Is this...
Didn't Ms. Aki seem way out of character?
Yeah, she's never spoken like that, has she?
She had that hardcore cutie character going, didn't she?
Yeah, but, after suddenly showing up and saying what she did,
I don't think we can trust her.
Hey!
So what, are you saying that Ms. Aki is tricking us?
For what reason?
None of you can ever go back to your world again!
What are you saying?
No way.
Why not?
You came here to find us, right?
Come on, I want to go home!
I thought you were here to rescue us!
We want to go home!
Shut up! Who do you think you're talking to?!
This was never about going home, was it?!
What do you mean by that?
There are those among you who could use your powers before—
that is, while you were still at school.
Which means...
that this whole "going adrift" thing might be the result of someone using their power!
Then...
can we ask how you made your way here?
Huh, that's a great question from a terrible waste of oxygen.
All right, listen up.
Because God needed me to, that's why!
Okay, but were there really those who could use their power at school?
After hearing what Ms. Aki said,
it kind of got me thinking.
There were some strange incidents at school, remember?
Like three billion yen flying out of the lockers,
and auroras appearing on the school grounds.
Thinking about it now, couldn't all of that have been the result of someone using their power?
So you think Ms. Aki was telling the truth?
But there's only one of us who could pull off something like that, right?
I hate to even bring this up, but...
What?
Well, uh...
What? Out with it.
He might just be pretending that he can't get back home to pull the wool over our eyes.
I don't get it.
I was kind of thinking that, too.
You mean he's been lying to us?
Is he for real?
Everyone be quiet! Settle down!
Damn it!
I swear, I'm gonna kill him!
Now, now, take it easy.
It's not possible for Nagara to be
pretending that we can't go home.
And why is that?!
If he was trying to trick us all,
then he never would have gone to other worlds.
That's right. Also, how can you suspect one of your classmates?
Doesn't that go against our school motto,
"Live in harmony"?
Magnificent.
You made this, right?
For everybody?
Made what?
I'm complimenting you. You're not happy?
It's not like I'm that big of a deal.
Why not?
Huh?
'Cause there's heaps of talented people out there.
And I don't just mean in this world—
That's where you're wrong.
It's thanks to this hole that the island has avoided sinking.
You're not like the others.
You're one of a kind.
I don't believe that.
You poor boy.
Nobody really understands. Not even you.
Y-You're crushing me, Teacher.
You are somebody special.
You don't have to be bound by this world.
The time is approaching.
You're going to evolve. It's something...
that only you can do.
This is incredible.
It has the power to unravel things.
This little guy is going to come in awfully handy.
Curious?
Those were supplied by other students who found power relics.
Power relics?
Yeah. That's kind of just what we started calling them.
They're like the manifestation of a power that you receive
whenever you beat a world.
Yeah? So the others already knew about these.
So, that includes these?
Those are Go-Old Glasses.
They allow you to see others as they'll look when they're old.
What?
Nothing.
I never imagined that powers could come in so many shapes and size.
The way home might even pop up unexpectedly.
Then you might be on before long.
Huh? Me?
Yeah, our savior.
C-Cut it out.
You know, Nagara...
Japan's greatest balding, toothless, wrinkled old lump!
What?
Well, it's just... right now, all the others...
kind of see you as the
opposite of a savior, you might say.
And, um, maybe even...
Good evening!
Is Nagara here?
We'd like to have a word with you, if that's okay.
Huh? With me?
Seriously? No, he's not doing it on purpose.
Nagara wouldn't do that.
Looking at the facts,
it's only natural to think so, isn't it?
Sure, he has his power, but it's wrong
to jump to conclusions based only on that.
That's why we asked him to come here.
This is a discussion.
We were hoping he could tell us all the truth.
Well, Nagara? Answer the question.
I-It wasn't me.
I'm...
I'm not the one who did this.
Look, you may not realize...
but we all have loved ones who we left behind.
Our parents will be worried sick waiting for us,
and some of us were studying hard for entrance exams.
Same goes for those in clubs.
We have to get back home.
That's not what I'm doing!
Unlike you, the rest of us are missed.
Say you're sorry!
Huh? What for?
Yeah, apologize for messing up everyone's lives!
I-I'm sor—
You don't have to apologize!
We're talking to Nagara!
This isn't a discussion.
You just want to pin all of this on someone to make yourselves feel better!
We're all acting pretty ugly,
and have been for some time.
I think we might have let
Ms. Aki's words get to us too much.
We've come this far by working together, haven't we?
Have you forgotten that?
Yeah, Hoshi's right.
Hey, where are you all going?
Sorry, but we're tired of his lectures.
So...
you're all willing to listen to Ms. Aki's lectures instead?
For starters, she declared that we can never go back to our world, right?
She then went on to invoke the name of God as to why she appeared in this world.
Don't you think that's strange?
You're not done with your compulsory education yet.
I'll be the one who shows you the way!
That isn't what you want, is it?
There's no salvation in that.
She isn't anyone's savior.
Your cheap tricks aren't going to save anyone either.
Still, it's the truth.
Do it right. You're not helping anyone like this.
I don't have the knack for it.
Knack's got nothing to do with this.
Right, nothing to do with it.
No matter where I go, or what power I have,
it always ends up the same.
My life has been like this ever since I was born.
So you're just going to give up again.
Being born doesn't magically give your life meaning.
That's something you have to work out on your own.
Thinking that everything we're given in life already has its value or meaning set
is like letting others decide for you, which is awful.
Yeah.
Oh, look!
Guardian spirits!
Whoa, wait, it's too dangerous!
Nagara, come on! It's incredible!
Nah, I'm good.
I'm telling you, it's safe! Come on, put your mask on!
Really?
Hurry up, already!
Wasn't that amazing? I've never seen them before!
Yeah, that was awesome.
I didn't think the guardian spirits were minnows.
For sure. That surprised me too.
Thanks.
Huh?
Worth it?
Yeah.
Still, I'm impressed that you could just dive in like that.
You're just too chicken.
And you're not nearly cautious enough.
But...
Do you ever get scared?
Sure I do. I get scared and anxious.
Then why?
But you know what?
That's exactly why I do it.
What's going to happen to us now?
It's all right.
We're ready for this.
We already know what's going to happen.
Running away again?
Huh?
Don't play dumb.
Your power is "Escape", the power to run away!
Your wanting to be somewhere else
has sucked everyone else into this world, too!
That isn't true.
Yes, it is!
Your power is just for running away—
that means you can't go home, can you?!
All of you are going to be dragged along on his escape forever!
Wait! You're wrong. I—
Shut up! She's not wrong!
[Coward!]
Knock it off, already. Quit making us suffer like this.
I-It's not like that. Listen to me—
You're enjoying yourself right now, aren't you?
Huh?
You just happened to gain an incredible power,
and now you've got girls being nice to you—
someone who was all but nonexistent back in our world.
I don't really care if I go back.
Whatever happens to you all, it doesn't matter to me.
Say that one more time.
I'm sorry.
Don't just apologize!
You always act like this, and pretend to give up,
when really, deep down, you're hoping for something!
So would you stop dragging the rest of us down with you, already?!
You see? He ran off again.
Sorry to always be a bother.
You believe in God, Rajdhani?
Oh, not in God per se, but I do have my faith.
I heard him speak to me once.
Who?
God. He told me that I was the one who caused us to go adrift.
What even is...
my power, anyway?
Found you!
Oh, good timing. Need some fish?
No matter what they say about you,
how I see you will never change.
I-I really do want to go back home, too...
Even though it's...
Stand up.
There's still time.
Can we really not go home anymore?
Give it up.
But...
After going to different worlds from the school,
we still made it back.
This world and your own world are two completely different things.
That girl, Nozomi, says that she can see the way out to our own world.
She's lying.
Hurry up and accept the truth already.
Besides, there is still some hope for you.
In him.
The guardian who protects this world.
O-Our savior!
Huh?
Have you been crying?
No, I haven't.
Oh, okay.
How did you get here?
You don't get to ask how,
after suddenly vanishing on us.
When we heard that you had disappeared,
the three of us went looking for you.
We went through a lot of trouble to get back here.
If the student council president hadn't let us borrow this,
we couldn't have made it.
Where's Nagara?!
Don't ask me.
Why did you run?
Tell us why you ran away!
Well, there was no getting through to them with words. I had no choice.
You had no choice?
If this is what it takes to satisfy them,
then it's good enough.
Don't take us for idiots!
You sit there like you're the only one with a sob story,
and scoff at everyone else around you!
Well, screw you!
Leave me alone.
Don't go running from the truth and fooling yourself!
The moment you run,
you become the same kind of idiot as the rest of them!
Leave me alone! Leave me alone!
This is what's so hopeless about you, Nagara.
I know...
You're not some cat.
Don't go running off without warning.
Indeed. We're really glad you're okay.
I'm sorry.
All right. No more running away.
Good. Let's go home.
Pff, so simpleminded.
You know, this looks familiar, doesn't it?
It reminds me a lot of the island we were first on.
The island that burned? Huh?
This is it, all right.
No doubt about it. This is the island we were on.
But that's strange.
That would mean there are two islands.
So that's it. We may have been working under a huge misunderstanding.
Nagara's power had another meaning.
We assumed that after the island burned,
it was restored by Asakaze's power.
But we were, in fact, wrong.
It was Nagara's power.
Huh? Nagara's power is teleporting, right?
Nagara's power is not a means of teleporting.
It's the power to create new worlds!
As is likely the case for every world we've ever gone to.
What an incredible view...
The light is so close!
That was an awful world.
No one was nice to me.
Do you want to change the world?
Would you like to come with me?
Yeah.